Microplastics have become a common source of pollution across the Earth — they have settled in the deep sea and on the Himalayas, stuck inside volcanic rocks, filled the stomachs of seabirds and even fallen in fresh Antarctic snow.
微塑料已成为地球上常见的污染源——它们沉积在深海和喜马拉雅山上，嵌在火山岩里，填满了海鸟的胃，甚至落在南极新下的雪中。
They are even appearing inside humans.
它们甚至出现在人体内。
Now, new research suggests that a simple, cheap measure may significantly reduce the level of microplastics in water from your tap: boiling and filtering it.
现在，新的研究表明，一个简单又便宜的方法或许能大大降低自来水中的微塑料含量：把水煮沸再过滤。
In a study published Wednesday in Environmental Science & Technology Letters, researchers from China found that boiling tap water for just five minutes — then filtering it after it cools — could remove at least 80 percent of its microplastics.
在周三发表于《环境科学与技术快报》的一项研究中，中国研究人员发现，只需把自来水煮沸五分钟，冷却后再过滤，就能去除其中至少80%的微塑料。
Crucially, this process relies on the water containing enough calcium carbonate to trap the plastics.
关键是，这个过程依赖于水中含有足够的碳酸钙来困住塑料。
In the study, boiling hard water containing 300 milligrams of calcium carbonate led to an almost 90 percent drop in plastics.
研究中，煮沸含有300毫克碳酸钙的硬水后，塑料减少了近90%。
But in samples with less than 60 milligrams of calcium carbonate, boiling reduced the level of plastics by just 25 percent.
但在碳酸钙含量低于60毫克的样本中，煮沸只让塑料含量降低了25%。
Additionally, the research didn’t include all types of plastics.
此外，这项研究并没有涵盖所有种类的塑料。
The team focused only on three common types — polystyrene, polyethylene and polypropylene — and they didn’t study other chemicals previously found in water such as vinyl chloride.
研究团队只关注了三种常见类型——聚苯乙烯、聚乙烯和聚丙烯——也没有研究以前在水中发现的其他化学物质，比如氯乙烯。
Still, the findings show a potential path forward for reducing microplastic exposure — a task that’s becoming increasingly difficult.
不过，这些发现指明了一条减少微塑料暴露的潜在途径——而这项任务正变得越来越困难。
Even bottled water, scientists found earlier this year, contains 10 to 1,000 times more microplastics than originally thought.
今年早些时候，科学家们发现，就连瓶装水所含的微塑料也是原先认为的10到1000倍。
Scientists are still trying to determine how harmful microplastics are — but what they do know has raised concerns.
科学家们仍在努力确定微塑料的危害有多大——但他们确实了解到的情况已经引起了担忧。
The new study suggests boiling tap water could be a tool to limit intake.
这项新研究表明，把自来水煮沸或许可以成为限制微塑料摄入量的一种手段。
“The way they demonstrated how microplastics were trapped through the boiling process was nice,” Caroline Gauchotte-Lindsay, an environmental engineer of the University of Glasgow in Scotland who was not involved in the research, tells New Scientist.
“他们展示微塑料如何在煮沸过程中被困住的方式很好，”未参与这项研究的苏格兰格拉斯哥大学环境工程师卡罗琳·高肖特-林赛对《新科学家》杂志表示。
“We should be looking into upgrading drinking water treatment plants so they remove microplastics.”
“我们应该研究升级饮用水处理厂，让它们能去除微塑料。”